《老男孩》
2013  美国
I hope so.
我希望如此
-All right, you guys gotta call me. -Yeah.
-好了，你们记得要给我打电话  -嗯
Make this happen. Make this happen, all right?
成功做到，成功做到，好吧？
See you guys. See you. All right.
再见，伙计们，再见，好了
-Joey, what's up? The usual? -Yeah.
-乔伊，怎么样？还是跟往常一样？  -对
-Thanks, Willy. -I hope you had a nice night.
-谢谢，威利  -希望你有个美好的夜晚
Yes, sir.
好的，先生
What about that new place?
新地方怎么样？
Oh, girl, I gotta go. Bye.
哦，我得挂了，再见
-You're late. -Time is a relative thing, doll.
-你迟到了  -时间是相对的，亲爱的
Mr. Hardigan, he's furious.
哈迪根先生，他非常生气
Mr. Blumenthal's threatening to take his business elsewhere.
布鲁门索尔先生威胁说 要把他的生意转到其他地方
Guy named Pat Vinelli said stay away from his sister or else.
有个叫帕特瓦内利的人说 要你离他妹妹还是什么人远点
-Patricia. Mm. Mm. -Oh, and this one, your ex-wife,
-帕特里夏，额，嗯  -噢，还有这个，你的前妻
Donna Hawthorne? She's really pissed.
唐娜·霍桑？她真的非常生气
-She's always pissed. -I don't blame her.
-她一直都非常生气  -我不怪她
Damn.
妈的
Mr. Sharkey, he's in his office.
夏基先生，他在他的办公室里
Ay-yi-yi.
哎呀呀呀
-There he is. -Hey, boss man.
-他在这儿  -嗨，老板
-Joe, how you doing? -Good. Oh!
-乔，你怎么样？  -很好哦！
Oh, I'm sorry. Oh, let me take a look at those.
噢，抱歉 噢，让我看看
-Watch the fight? -I didn't. I was working.
-看昨晚的拳击比赛了吗？  -没有，我当时在工作
Talk to me about Newcombe. Are you gonna bag him?
跟我说说纽科姆你一定要拿下这个家伙
This is a make it or break it for us. Got dinner tonight at the Pinnacle.
今晚我们在品尼克酒店一起吃晚饭
-Pinnacle? Oof. Expensive. -Yup. Oof. Necessary.
-品尼克酒店？喔，很贵啊  -是，但需要这样
-All right, reel him in. -I always do.
-好，把他拉入我们  -我一直都在这样做
If you don't, we're fucked. Now, let me make this very clear.
如果你不把拉入我们，我们就完蛋了  让我说得清楚点
-If you don't, -I'm...
-如果你不行  -我…
-you're fucked. -Got it. I got the deal.
-你就完蛋了  -知道了，我会拿下这桩生意的
Clean yourself up a little bit. Put on your best suit. Wear cologne, smell good.
把你自己打扮一下穿上你的西装 喷点古龙水，闻起来香
-Aramis. That chickie of his likes you. -Love it.
-阿拉米斯，他的女人喜欢你  -太棒了
-You knock them out, champ. -I will. Bob and weave. Bob and weave.
-你一定要拿下他们，冠军 -我会的，左挡右闪，左挡右闪
Boxing.
拳击
Primitive.
原始未开化
-Yeah, Joe Doucett.  -That was a long lunch.
-你好，乔杜塞特  -午饭时间可真长啊
-What can I do for you? -You know what day this is?
-我能为你做什么？  -你知道今天是什么日子吗？
Yes, I do. It's the 8th of October,
是，我知道，今天是10月8号
the year of our Lord 1993, which means that I'm late with my child support again.
1993年的今天我们的女儿诞生 这意味着我的子女抚养费又交迟了
That is not why I'm calling, you know it.
那不是我给你打电话的原因，你知道的
I asked you to come to Mia's party three weeks ago, you never called me back.
我三个星期前就告诉你来参加米娅的聚会 可你从来不回我
-Well, I can't make it, Donna. - Why not?
-我去不了，唐娜  -为什么来不了？
-Because I have a big client dinner. - Ha. Well, that's way more important
-因为我有一个非常重要的客户晚餐 -喔，那真是比你女儿的生日
- than your daughter's birthday.  -Listen, she is 3 years old, okay?
-要重要多了  -听着，她只有三岁，好吗？
Three years old, okay? Do you think she cares whether I'm there or not?
三岁，好吗？你觉得她会在意我去没去吗？
You know what, Joe?
你知道吗，乔？
As a husband, as a father,
作为一个丈夫，作为一个父亲，
-you are a fucking joke! -You know what? You're a bitch, Donna.
-你真是个他妈的笑话！ -你知道吗？你是个婊子，唐娜
-What did you say? -You're a fucking bitch!
-你说什么？  -你是个贱婊子！
- Fuck...  -Fuck!
-操…  -操！
We don't make ads for Joe Doakes.
我们不为乔都克做广告
No, John Q. Public, John and Jane Doe, Mr. Everyman.
不，约翰Q 大众，约翰和简多，普通人
No, no, no.
不，不，不
We make ads for Daniel Newcombe.
我们为丹尼尔纽科姆做广告
We make ads for Joe Doucett.
我们为乔杜塞特做广告
We cater to the elite, the crème de la crème.
我们为精英服务 [法语]精英中的精英
Celebrities, athletes, entertainers, rappers.
名人，运动员，演艺人员，说唱歌手
All in a Daniel Newcombe fine motor vehicle. That's what I'm gonna do for you.
在丹尼尔纽科姆的豪华车的所有人 那就是我要为你做的
-It's a really great idea. -It's a great idea. Listen to the lady.
-这是个非常了不起的主意 -这是个了不起的主意，听这位女士的
-I'm gonna give you a shot. -That's what I like to hear.
-我给你一次机会  -这就是我想要听到的
-Call me at the office first thing Monday. -I will do so, sir.
-周一早上首先要做的就是给我打电话 -我会的，先生
I've gotta make a call. Please excuse me.
我得去打个电话，不好意思．
You gotta do business when you gotta do business.
你需要做生意的时候你得去做生意
-Don't be long? Okay. -I'll be right back, baby.
-别太长了，好吗？  -我很快就回来，宝贝儿
-A beautiful couple. -He's the best.
-一对漂亮的夫妻  -他是最棒的
You won't regret it. I promise you.
你不会后悔的，我保证
Congratulations.
恭喜
Thank you, Judy. I don't think I could've done that without you.
谢谢你，朱迪 我觉得没有你我是成功不了的
Oh, sure you could've.
噢，你当然会成功
Laughing at all my jokes, telling him what great ideas I have.
我讲的所有笑话都笑，告诉他我的主意是多么好
-They are great ideas. -I appreciate that.
-他们确实是好主意  -我很感激，真的
From one bullshit artist to another. Listen.
从一个骗子到另一个骗子  听着
I was thinking, what do you say you and I,
我在想，你觉得我和你
we get together this weekend, ditch the old man,
我们这周聚到一起，抛弃那个老男人
bottle of Scotch, eight ball of coke,
喝杯威士忌加可乐
dirty movies on Skinemax?
看点重口味色情片儿？
-Excuse me? -What? Heh.
-不好意思？  -什么？
Let me get this straight.
让我弄明白点
You think I said those things because I wanna fuck you?
你觉得我说那些话 是因为我想跟你上床？
-Yeah. -No.
-是的  -不
-No? -No. I wanna get out of here
-不？  -不，我想要离开这儿
and away from you as fast as humanly possible.
尽快地离你远点儿
-Daniel likes you, God knows why. -Okay.
-丹尼尔喜欢你，谁知道为什么  -好
-But, Joe? -Yeah?
-但是，乔？  -嗯？
You're a dick.
你是个混蛋
And I would rather fuck a corpse.
我宁愿干一具尸体
Joe.
乔
-You wanna disrespect me? -No. I didn't...
-你想要羞辱我？  -不，我没有…
-That's all right. -It was just a misunderstanding.
-那没关系 没关系  -那只是个误会
-I'm a big boy. I'm a big boy. -I can take it.
-我是个大男人，我是个大男人  -我可以接受
Okay.
好
But you disrespect the woman I love, son, that's...
但是你羞辱我喜欢的女人，龟孙子，那就…
-That's just plain stupid. -It was just a misunderstanding.
-那真的是非常蠢  -这是个误会
Let's go, baby.
我们走吧，宝贝儿
He's not worth the trouble.
他不值得这些麻烦
Mm.
唔
Mm. Uh!
唔 呃！
I'm dry!
我酒没了！
Does anybody have any more alcohol?
有人还有酒吗？
Shut the fuck up!
闭上你他妈的嘴！
Does anyone have more alcohol?
有人还有酒吗？
Whoa.
哦
I can't...
我不能…
# I don't wanna go anymore ##
? 我不想再去了 ??
Hey, wait up!
嗨，等等！
U.S.A.
美国
U.S.A. Whoa!
美国 喔！
What is that?
那是什么？
I know what that is.
我知道那是什么
-What have you got? -Five dollar.
-你有什么  -5美元
What? I haven't even touched anything yet.
什么？我还没碰任何东西呢
Okay?
好吗？
-How much is that? -Five dollar.
-这个多少钱  -5美元
Ah...
啊…
My daughter.
我女儿
She's gonna be 3 years old.
她马上就要3周岁了
It's her birthday.
今天是她生日
-Give me 5 dollar. -Three years old.
-给我5美元  -3岁
Three years old.
3岁
-Spec... -Give me 5 dollar.
-特别…  -给我5美元
You give me 5 dollar.
你给我5美元
Mwah.
喔
Oh...
噢…
No.
不
Stop it.
别闹了
Hey.
嗨
Hey!
嗨！
Chucky!
查基！
-Chucky! -We're closed.
-查基！  -我们打烊了！
No! It's Joe!
别，我是乔！
Are you deaf? I said we're closed.
你聋了吗？我说我们关门了
Joe! Open up.
我是乔！开门！
Hey! Come on! Give me one drink.
嗨，快点，给我杯喝的
-Come on. One... -Coffee.
-就一杯…  -咖啡
No. Fuck coffee.
不，去他妈的咖啡
-No, you promised. -You promised.
-不，你保证  -你保证
-You promised. -You promised. Tell the duck.
-你保证  -你保证，跟鸭子说
I don't wanna tell the duck. Come back tomorrow. You'll thank me in the morning.
我不想跟鸭子说话 明天再来吧 你明天早上会谢我的
No! No!
不！不！
Fuck, no! Ah!
操，不！啊！
Goddamn it.
去他妈的
You don't wanna have fun!
你不想找点乐子！
Nobody wants to have fun anymore.
没人想要找乐子了
Goddamn it.
去他妈的
Hey.
嗨
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Hi.
你好
Hey, I'm gonna take a piss, all right?
嗨，我要尿尿，行吗？
Okay?
好吗？
Oh. Sorry about the toilet.
噢，抱歉 用了厕所
I didn't mean...
我不想…
Hello?
你好？
Underwear.
内衣
What the hell is this?
这他妈是什么？
Where the fuck is the phone?
电话在什么地方？
Hello?
你好？
Can anybody hear me?
有人能听到我吗？
Hello?
你好？
Son of a bitch.
该死的
Hello?
你好？
Can anybody hear me on the outside?
外面有人能听到我吗？
I'm stuck in a motel room.
我被困在一个汽车旅馆里
Hello?
你好？
Fuck!
操！
Hello?
你好？
Hey. Hey.
嗨，嗨
Tell me why I'm here. Tell... No, listen.
告诉我我为什么在这儿告诉我…不，听着
Tell me why I'm here. No, no, no.
告诉我为什么在这儿别，不，不
Ah. Ow.
噢，呃
Dumplings. Anything but dumplings.
饺子，只有饺子
Please.
求你了
Please can I have something else to eat?
能给我点别的吃吗？
Jesus H. Christ, God love you,
基督上帝，上帝保佑你
give me something other than this crap.
给我点别的东西吃，除了这些臭饺子
We're gonna squeeze for two
我们来挤压两次
and then we're gonna open for two. Make sure you resist it.
然后我们打开两次确保你腿上的压力
This is a great way to tone and strengthen your upper legs.
这是增强你大腿的好方法
And we all know that's an area that often gets neglected.
我们都知道有一个区域经常被忽视
So, if you haven't already, join with me now.
所以，如果你还没有开始，现在就跟我一起来做吧
And squeeze.
挤压
Come on, and up. Good.
快点，向上，好
- Can you feel the burn?  -Yes.
-你能感受到脂肪在燃烧吗？  -是的
- And release.  -Release.
-放松  -放松
Here we go.
我们继续
- And...  -Squeeze.
-然后…  -挤压
And release.
然后放松
- Let's go, keep going. Squeeze.  -Squeeze.
-开始，继续，挤压  -挤压
And up. Ahh.
向上 啊
Ahh.
啊
- Ahh.  -Ahh.
-啊  -啊
Now we're gonna speed it up.
现在我们要加速了
-Oh, yeah. - Ahh.
-噢，好  -啊
-Ahh. Ooh. - Ahh.
-啊，喔  -啊
- Good. Feel it.  -I am.
-好，感受它  -我正在感受
Ahh. Ahh.  Ahh. Mm. Oh.
-啊 啊  -啊 嗯 噢
Ahh. Ahh.
啊 啊
Good, and open.
好，打开
Good, and squeeze. And...
好，然后挤压 然后…
Good. Squeeze.
好，挤压
And open.
然后打开
Squeeze.
挤压
And open.
然后打开
There she is.
他在这儿
I owe you one.
我欠你一个
Early this morning, the body of single mother Donna Hawthorne
今天上午早些时候，单亲母亲唐娜·霍桑的尸体
was discovered in her Southside apartment.
在她公寓南边被发现
Police confirmed that she was raped and savagely beaten to death.
警方声称她被强奸并被残忍地打死
The victim was the mother of a 3-year-old girl
受害者是一名三岁女孩的母亲
who was inside the apartment at the time of the killing.
小女孩在案发时就在公寓里
To quote forensic investigators:
法院检察官说
The evidence is irrefutable.
证据确凿
Prime suspect Joseph Doucett was the victim's former husband
犯罪嫌疑人乔·瑟夫·杜塞特是受害者的前夫
and father of the surviving child.
和这个幸存孩子的父亲
That's all from Stephanie Lee, here on the scene. Back to you, Michael.
我是斯蒂芬妮·李，从现场发来的报道回到转播间，迈克尔
Remember,
记住
your enemy is most vulnerable just before he strikes.
你的敌人在他进攻前是最脆弱的
This area is extremely dangerous. Don't let your guard down for a second.
这里非常危险，千万不要放松你的警惕
They're everywhere.
他们随处都在
This is really big.
这真的很大
We need to think about what our next move will be.
我们需要想想我们的下一步是什么
We must figure out a plan and execute it.
我们必须想出一个计划并执行计划
More importantly, we need to get you two together.
更重要的事，我们需要让你们两个在一起
-You have to speak with him.   -Unfortunately, it didn't work.
-你得跟他谈一谈  -不幸的是，这没用
He's still alive.
他还活着
We're going to have to try something else.
我们得试试其他方法
I don't know. That seems risky.
我不知道  那看起来很冒险
If those two guys are who we think they are...
如果那两个人是我们想像的那样…
I am sorry.
我很抱歉
Six, seven, eight.
六，七，八
Up, down. Let's take it down, down, slow.
上，下往下，往下，慢一点
Down, down, slow.
往下，往下，慢一点
Take it lower.
低一点
That's it, bring it up.
就是这样，抬起来
Down, down, slow.
往下，往下，慢一点
Arch your back. That's it.
弯腰，就是这样
That's it.
就是这样
Recover before we get back into it.
我们下一遍之前先休息一下
I, William Jefferson Clinton, do solemnly swear
我，威廉姆·杰斐逊·克林顿发誓
I will faithfully execute the office of president...
我会真诚地执行总统的职能…
Come on this way.
来，这边
Mm. Mm, mm.
嗯 嗯 嗯
You're the king.
你是国王
Don't ever leave me.
不要离开我
Oh, I won't touch your babies.
噢，我不会碰你的孩子的
I won't touch your babies.
我不会碰你的孩子
I'll keep you nice and comfy here.
我会让你好好地舒服地在这儿生活
Yes, you protect those babies.
是的，你要保护这些孩子
You protect those babies.
你要保护这些孩子
Where are you?
你在哪儿？
Aah! No!
啊！不！
No, no, no!
不，不，不！
No!
不！
I'm sorry.
对不起
No.
不
Huh.
呵
Uh...
嗯…
Tonight on Mysteries of Crime:
今晚的犯罪之谜
July 30th, 1994.
1994年7月30曰
Donna Hawthorne is brutally raped and beaten to death
唐娜·霍桑被残忍地
by her ex-husband, Joseph Doucett.
被她前夫，乔·瑟夫·杜塞特奸杀
It's an open-and-shut case, but there's just one problem.
这是个既算没结又算结了的案子，只有一个问题
The killer has disappeared.
凶手消失了
For five years Joe Doucett has eluded justice.
五年了，乔杜塞特逃过了法律制裁
Where could this fiend be hiding?
这个魔鬼会藏在哪儿呢？
I'm James Prestley.
我是詹姆斯·普雷斯利
Tonight, we examine this mystery of crime.
今晚，我们会探讨这起犯罪之谜
What can you tell us about Mia?
你能告诉我们有关米娅的事情吗？
We adopted Mia shortly after the tragedy.
我们在悲剧发生之后不久就领养了米娅
Neither her mother or this Doucett murderer
她的母亲和这个杜塞特凶手
had any living relatives
都没有任何在世的亲戚
so we were lucky enough to... Blessed.
所以我们很幸运…幸福
Yeah.
是的
We were blessed to have this angel come into our lives.
我们很幸福能有这样一位天使进入我们的生活
-Does Mia know what happened?   -No.
-米娅知道发生的事情吗？  -不
I mean, she knows she's adopted and that her real mother is gone
我的意思是，她知道她是被领养的 她的生母去世了
but no more than that.
但仅仅就知道这些
We're waiting until she's older to tell her.
我们准备等到她大一点之后再告诉她
I wanted to talk to Mia, but instead, Ken and Shirley Roos
我本想要跟米娅聊一聊，但是，肯和雪莉·鲁斯
let us watch their daughter do what she loves best.
让我们看着他们的女儿 做她喜爱做的事就行了
Ah... Ah.
啊… 啊
Yay.
好啊
"Dear daughter, dear Mia,
亲爱的女儿，亲爱的米娅
I saw you on TV today. You looked very pretty.
我今天在电视上看到你了 你看起来很漂亮
When you played your cello, it was so beautiful.
你演奏大提琴时，非常美
I'm glad that you're happy.
我很高兴看到你很快乐
That you're being taken care of by such nice people.
很高兴看到你被这样的好人领养
I wish it were me.
我希望那是我
I'm writing to you to tell you."
我给你写信是要告诉你
Lift your arms. Bend your right knee.
抬起你的胳膊，弯下你的右膝盖
That today I vow to change.
那天我发誓要改变
And today, I pledge to fight against the impulses
今天，我发誓要控制住
that poison my body
囚禁我身体的冲动
No, no, no,  and my mind
不，不，不  囚禁我的内心
and my soul.
和灵魂的冲动
And I do this, dear daughter,
亲爱的女儿，我这样做
for you
是为了你
In hopes that one day you will see me not for who I was
希望有一天你不会看到我曾经的样子
- but for who I am. -Squeeze.
-而是我现在的样子  -挤压
- And I know that you hate me. -Good.
-我知道你恨我  -好
And I deserve your hate
你应该恨我
But not for the death of your mother.
但不是因为你母亲的死
No...
不…
"I did not kill her.
我没有杀她
I deserve your hate because I was never a father to you.
你应该恨我 因为我对你从没有尽过父亲的责任
Until now."
知道现在
Five, four,
五，四
three, two, one.
三，二，一
Are you Andrew Blumenthal?
你是安德鲁·布鲁门索尔吗？
Are you Daniel Newcombe?
你是丹尼尔·纽科姆吗？
Oh!
噢！
Are you Patrick Vinelli?
你是帕特里克·瓦内利吗？
Mr. Sharkey?
夏基先生？
Richard Dennison?
理查德·丹尼森？
Are you Kenny Flowers?
你是肯尼·弗劳尔斯吗？
Samuel Carver?
萨缪尔·卡佛？
Are you Mark Atlas?
你是马克·亚特兰斯吗？
We've fought for the cause of liberty and for the peace of the world.
我们为了世界的自由和和平而战
Are you Bill Myers?
你是比尔·迈尔斯吗？
Are you Tom Marshall?
你是汤姆·马歇尔吗？
We are facing a storm that most of us have feared.
我们正面临着一场我们大多数人都害怕的风暴
The storm is now a category five
风暴现在已经是五级
with sustained winds of 150 miles an hour
伴随着150英里每小时的持续强风
with wind gusts of 190 miles per hour.
和190英里每小时的阵风
I will get out.
我会出去的
And whoever you are,
不管你是谁
wherever you are,
你在哪儿
I will find you.
我都会找到你
...preserve, protect and defend
…保留，保护，和捍卫
The Constitution of the United States.
美国宪法
- So help you God. -So help me God.
-所以，愿上帝帮你  -所以，请上帝帮我
Freedom is yours. You can do it.
自由是你的  你能做到
Keep pushing, keep breathing. Feel the inner peace within you.
继续推，保持呼吸  感受你身体内部的平静
Another chance to freedom.
自由的另一个机会
It's always there for you.
总是在那儿等你
That's everything. Back to you, Ray.
就是这样，回到你那边，雷
91，92
九十一、九十二
93，94
九十三、九十四
94.
九十四
"Dear daughter, today I leave this place,
“亲爱的女儿，今天我要离开这个地方
this prison.
这个监狱
And once I'm free, I will get these letters to you, somehow.
一旦我自由了，我会把这些信件给你
All I ask, Mia, is that you read them before you judge me.
我所要求的，米娅，就是你在评判我之前先读读它们
I beg you.
我求你了
Please.
求你了
Your loving father."
爱你的父亲”
Over 20 years on the air.
20年无影无踪
This season we look back
这一季我们回过头看看
at the greatest mysteries of crime in our history.
我们历史上那些伟大的犯罪之谜
Tonight,
今晚
the murder of Donna Hawthorne. Tell me about your mother.
唐娜·霍桑的谋杀者  告诉我你的母亲
I don't remember my mother,
我不记得我母亲了
but I know I loved her.
但是我知道我爱她
I know it in my heart and my soul.
我知道我内心和我灵魂深处我爱她
And your father?
那你的父亲呢？
I don't remember him, either.
我也不记得他了
I'm sorry, that's not what I was asking.
我很抱歉，那不是我问的
I hate him for what he did.
我恨他所做的
No, there's a part of me that hates him for what he did
不，我身体里一部分恨他所做的
but there's another part that wants to understand,
但另一部分想要去理解他
that wants to ask why.
想要问他为什么
Your father's been missing for 20 years.
你的父亲已经失踪20年了
I don't know if you presume he's dead
我不知道，如果你假设他已经死了
but if I could somehow bring him here, do you think you could forgive him?
但是如果假设我把他带到这儿了，你认为你能原谅他吗？
Uh...
呃…
I could try.
我会尝试
Mia Roos is a beautiful and very talented young woman
米娅·鲁靳是个漂亮的非常有天赋的年轻女子
but what's most impressive about her is her gentle and compassionate spirit.
但是她最动人的地方是她温柔而慈悲的灵魂
I only hope that she's able to find some kind of closure one day.
我只希望她有一天能得到某种解脱
This mystery may remain unsolved, but one thing is clear.
这个谜可能一直解不开，但是有一件事是清楚的
Justice always prevails.
邪不胜正
I'm James Prestley.
我是詹姆斯·普雷斯利
God bless you.
上帝保佑你
Hey.
嘿
Hey, slow down a second.
嘿，等我一下
Stop.
停下
-Get the fuck off of me! -Hey!
-放开我！  -嗨！
Leave the lady alone.
放开那位女士
Leave her the fuck alone.
不要打扰她
Stop! Stop! Wait!
住手！住手！等一下！
Please! No! No!
求你了，不要！不！
No!
不！
Stop! Stop!
住手！住手！
Stop! Please!
住手！求你了！
Please!
求你了！
Let him know I stopped by, all right?
告诉他我过来过，好吗？
Hey. Where is she?
嗨，她在哪儿？
Tell me where she is!
告诉我她在哪儿！
-Don't hurt me! -Where is she?
-不要伤害我！  -她在哪儿？
Hey! Let him go!
嗨！放开他！
Jesus, let go of him!
天啊，放开他！
Jesus, Johnny, are you okay?
天啊，约翰尼，你没事吧？
If you wanna see the doctor, respect the rules, okay?
如果你想要看医生，遵守规则，好吗？
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起，抱歉
-I thought he was someone else. -You okay?
-我认错人了  -你没事吧？
-Is everything all right? -Yeah, yeah, everything's fine.
-这里没事吧？  -是，是的，没事
That must be yours. Johnny takes things that don't belong to him sometimes.
那一定是你的约翰尼 有时会拿不是他的东西
I'm really sorry about that. Hey, I'm Dr. Tom Melby. I run the clinic.
我真的很抱歉！你好，我是汤姆·梅尔比医生 我经营这个诊所
I'm Joe Doakes.
我是乔·杜克斯
Johnny, can we give Mr. Doakes his umbrella back?
约翰尼，我们能把杜克斯先生的雨伞还给他吗？
-Please? -No.
-可以吗？  -不
-No' he can keep it- -You sure?
-是的，他可以留着它  -你确定？
Sir? Uh, Joe? Um, uh...
先生？嗯，乔？嗯，呃…
Sorry. If you think that you might need any medical help
对不起，如果你觉得你需要任何医疗帮助
or, you know, if you just... If you just wanna talk to
或者是，你仅仅…想跟人说说话
someone, my name is Marie Sebastian.
我的名字是玛丽·塞巴斯蒂安
Please, take that.
请你拿着这个吧
We're closed!
我们关门了！
Are you deaf? I said, we're closed!
你聋了吗？我说我们关门了！
Chucky.
查基
Do I know you?
我认识你吗？
It's Joe.
我是乔
Joe?
乔？
Come in.
进来
Twenty years in the same room?
在同一个房间被关了20年？
Jesus Christ, I would have lost my mind.
天啊，我肯定会疯掉的
Ahh. Why?
为什么呢？
Why would somebody do that to you? What could you have possibly done?
为什么有人要对你那样？你做过什么？
Here, I think you could use this.
来，我觉得你可以来点这个
-No, I'm fine with coffee. -Well, what are you gonna do, Joe?
-不，我喝咖啡就行了  -好吧，那你打算干什么，乔？
Hello?
你好？
Hello, Joseph. How was your first day of freedom?
你好，乔·瑟夫  你自由的第一天感觉怎么样？
-Who is this? - "I believe
-你是谁？  -我相信
that we are solely responsible for our choices,
我们要完全为自己的选择负责任
and we have to accept the consequences
而且我们要接受后果
of every deed, word and thought throughout our lifetime. "
我们生命中每件事，说的每句话，每个想法的后果
That was written by Elisabeth Kübler-Ross, Joseph.
这是伊丽莎白·库伯勒·罗斯写的，乔·瑟夫
And now, I want you to look at every
现在，我想要你去看看
deed, word and thought
你悲惨的人生中
in the course of your miserable existence.
每件事，每句话，每个想法
Heh. There's more coming.
哼，还有
A formal proposal
一份正式的提议
that if you are successful, Joseph, I think you will find peace.
如果你成功了，乔·瑟夫，我觉得你会找到平静
I believe you may even find happiness.
我相信你甚至会找到幸福
Perhaps with that lovely daughter of yours, Mia.
或许是跟你可爱的女儿，米娅
-Mia has nothing to do with this. - Anyway, I'll be in touch.
-米娅跟这件事无关  -无论如何，我会联系你的
Was that him? Let me see.
那是他吗？让我看看
Blocked. What'd he say?
屏蔽了 他说什么？
I need your help, Chucky.
我需要你的帮助，查基
Okay, Daniel Newcombe.
好，丹尼尔·纽科姆
Probably gonna be a lot of Daniel Newcombes.
可能会有很多丹尼尔·纽科姆
He owned a bunch of car dealerships.
他拥有很多汽车经销商
Daniel Newcombe Fine Motor Cars.
丹尼尔·纽科姆豪华汽车行
Well...
好吧…
"Local businessman killed in mid-air collision."
当地商人在空难中丧生
We can take him off the list.
我们可以把他从名单上去掉了
You know, if you don't mind me saying,
你知道，恕我直言
-that's a very long list. -I know.
-那是个很长的名单  -我知道
-Bernard Sharkey. -Yeah.
-伯纳德·夏基  -是
Advanced, uh...
高级，呃…
Advanced Advertising.
高级广告
"Never Say Die Senior Citizen Club."
“从不言死高级会所”
-That's him? -Yeah.
-那是他吗？  -是的
Why is he on the list?
他为什么在名单上？
Because he was my boss. Is there an address?
因为他是我的老板 有地址吗？
-Uh, yeah. This guy? -Okay.
-有，这个家伙？  -好
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You can check him out.
是，是，是 你可以查一查他
-What'd he do? -Oh, it's what I did, not what he did.
-他做了什么？  -哦，是我做了什么，不是他做了什么
-Save him. -Mm-hm.
-留着他  -嗯
What do you have to do? Just write it in there?
你要做什么？仅仅在那儿写上就行了？
Yeah. You write whatever you want in there and then you hit enter. That's all.
是的，你在那儿写什么都行，然后你敲“enter”键就行了
-I can do the rest. -No, I'm good.
-剩下的我来做吧  -不用，我还行
-No, why don't you go to sleep? -You sure?
-不了，你先去睡觉吧  -你确定吗？
-Yeah. -All right.
-是  -好吧
Joe.
乔
Got some coffee.
我拿了点咖啡
Joe! Joe!
乔！乔！
Hey! Hey, man!
嗨！嗨！兄弟！
Come on.
挺住
Hey, man! Hey!
嗨，兄弟！嗨！
911 operator, what's your emer...?
911接线员，你有什么紧急情况…？
He gonna be all right?
他会没事吧？
Yeah, he'll be fine. He just needs to rest. Guy's exhausted.
是的，他会没事的 他只是需要休息 这家伙精疲力尽了
He's also malnourished and dehydrated.
他还有营养不良和脱水
What happened to him?
他发生什么了？
He showed up last night completely out of the blue.
他昨晚突然出现
I haven't seen the guy in 20 years. I didn't even recognize him at first.
我20年没见他了，我刚开始甚至没认出他
Comes inside, we sit down, he starts telling me this crazy story.
进来后，我们坐下，他开始告诉我他的疯狂的故事
What's the story?
什么故事？
-How do you know him? -I don't.
-你怎么认识他的？  -我不认识他
-You don't. -Well, what's the story?
-你不认识他  -怎么？什么故事？
I said enough already. I don't know who you are.
我已经说了很多了 我不知道你是谁
Come on, Chucky!
快 查基！
-It's 9:00 already! -Shit.
-已经9点了！  -糟糕
Okay, I gotta open the joint.
好了，我得去把门头打开了
Okay. I'm gonna stick around and make sure he's all right for a while.
好，我在这儿留一会儿，确保他没事
Hold your horses.
别着急
Dear daughter, dear Mia,
亲爱的女儿，亲爱的玛丽
I have been unjustly held in this god-awful place for almost 20 years.
我已经在这个糟糕的地方 被非法囚禁了将近20年了
When I'm free of this place, and I will be free of it,
当我离开这个地方的时候，我会离开这个地方的
my purpose will be simple and pure.
我的目的很简单很单纯
I intend to prove my love for you.
我想要证明我对你的爱
To do this, I must find the man who put me here.
为了做到这个，我必须找到把我关在这儿的人
I am your father.
我是你的父亲
Now it is my duty,
现在这是我的义务
now it is my responsibility
我的责任
to take care of you.
来照顾你
To love you, Mia. Please give me that chance.
为了能爱你，米娅，请给我这个机会
The world can be a cold, ugly place, and people can be cruel and deceitful.
世界可能是个冷酷丑陋的地方，人们也可能是残忍欺诈的
But never let that change who you are.
但是千万不要让那些东西改变了你
One day I will be there to share it with you.
有一天我会跟你一起分享这些
Love, Daddy.
爱你的爸爸
You read them?
你读了这些信？
You read my letters?
你读了我的信？
You had no right!
你没有权利读！
Who the fuck are you?
你他妈是谁？
Chucky called me because you were in bad shape.
查基打电话给我 因为你身体不好
-I'm all right now, you can get out. -No, you're far from all right.
-我现在好了，你可以走了  -不，你一点都不好
What are you doing here?
你在这儿做什么？
I apologize for reading your letters.
我为读了你的信向你道歉
You didn't call the police?
你没有报警？
-No, I didn't. -Why?
-没，我没有  -为什么？
-I believe you. -Why?
-我相信你  -为什么？
I believe that you've been locked up for a long time.
我相信你被关起来很长时间
Okay? I believe you want to be a father to your daughter.
好吗？我相信你想要成为你女儿的父亲
Don't touch me.
别碰我
And that you want to prove your love to her.
而且你想要证明你对她的爱
-Okay. -I said, don't touch me.
-好  -我说过了，别碰我
Unh! Okay.
呃！好
What if I thought you knew too much, huh?
如果我觉得你知道的太多了呢？
Reading my letters.
读了我的信
What if I felt like I needed to kill you right now?
如果我觉得我有必要现在就杀了你呢？
Then I suppose I'd be dead.
那么我想我早就已经死了
Joe,
乔
please take your hands off me.
请把你的手从我身上拿开
If you are trying to find your daughter
如果你想找到你的女儿
and clear your name, I could help you. Or let me take you to people who can.
证明你的清白，我可以帮你 或者让我带你去找那些能帮你的人
There are social workers, legal aid, even oops I trust.
有义工，法律援助，甚至我信任的警察
No, I don't need your help.
不，我不需要你的帮助
Bernard Sharkey.
伯纳德·夏基
Oh. Bernard. He's up the stairs. It's nice of y'all to come.
噢，伯纳德他在楼上 你们能来真好
He doesn't get many visitors.
来看他的人并不多
-Thank you. -Bye. Enjoy.
-谢谢  -再见
Sorry, boss.
对不起，老板
-How do you know that's not him? -He seems happy.
-你怎么知道不是他？  -他看起来很幸福
The one who called me doesn't know what happy means.
那个打电话给我的人不知道什么是幸福
-What? -I need Yellow Pages.
-什么？  -我需要黄页
-Where are all the payphones? -No. Okay. Hold on.
-付费电话在哪儿？  -不，好，等一下！
-What are you looking for? -A restaurant.
-你在找什么？  -一家餐厅
-Okay. -It's called Dragon something.
-好  -叫做龙什么的餐厅
There. Here.
这儿
Five dollar.
5美元
Sir, buy something for your girlfriend. Only $5.
先生，给你的女朋友买点东西吧  仅仅5美元
Buy anything, $5.
任何商品，5美元
Ugh.
呃
I have to go. I have a shift, I can't just not show up.
我得走了，我要换班，我不能不去
I put my number in your phone.
我把我的号码存进你的手机了
-I'll be free all day tomorrow. -Thank you.
-我明天一整天都没事  -谢谢
-The usual, sir?  -Yep. Thank you.
-和往常一样？先生  -是的，谢了
-Yeah. -Put it on the bill.
-好  -记账
Have a good day. See you tomorrow.
生活愉快 明天见
Where's my next order?
我下一个订单在哪儿？
Sir. Excuse me, sir. Sir!
先生，对不起，先生，先生
Hey.
嘿
You know the drill. Put it on the table.
你知道规矩  把它放在桌子上
Thirty-nine across. "Alter ego of Edmond Dantès."
39横向词是“爱德蒙唐泰斯的至交”
The Count of Monte Cristo.
基督山伯爵
Hello. It's time to feed the pets.
嗨，到了喂宠物的时间了
F-O-O-D. F-O-O-D.
食物，食物
Goddamn, these motherfuckers don't do shit.
妈的，这些混蛋什么都不做
Hey, what's up with the...? Unh!
嗨，发生了什么…？啊！
Let me up out of here, motherfucker. Me and you, man-to-man. Come on. Let's go.
让我离开这儿，混蛋我和你，单挑，来啊
Shit.
操
You want some get back, then let me get up.
你想要回扣，那就让我起来
Me and you can go at it, motherfucker. How about it?
我和你可以一起分享，混蛋，怎么样？
Hold still.
别动
What the fuck are you doing?
你他妈在做什么？
-What the fuck are you doing? -Shut the fuck up.
-你他妈在做什么？  -闭上你他妈的嘴
There we go.
我们开始
Are you ready?
你准备好了吗？
Might wanna think about what you're doing.
你应该想想你在做什么
I've been thinking about it for the last 20 years.
我已经想了20年了
Wait. What...?
等等，等…？
Hold still. Cocksucker.
别动  混蛋
Ow! Ow! Motherfucker. Ow!
啊！啊！混蛋，啊！
Shit.
操！
Heh, heh. You no dick, ass-licking son of a bitch!
啊，啊  你个太监，混蛋！
-Fuck you. -No, fuck you.
-操你妈的  -不，操你妈
Oh! You booger-eating, piss-drinking motherfucker.
啊！你去吃屎吧，你个混蛋！
If you stop now, you may get out of here alive.
如果你现在停下，或许你还可以活着离开这儿
I'm gonna keep going
我打算继续
till I can pull your head off with my bare hands.
直到我能空手把你的头拉下来
Okay?
好吗？
Listen to me. Listen to me.
听我说，听我说
I only run this place, all right?
我仅仅管理这里，好吗？
I was hired to keep you here.
有人雇我把你关在这儿
Who hired you?
谁雇的你？
-I can't tell you that. -Then do me a favor
-我不能告诉你  -那么帮我一个忙
and shut the fuck up.
闭上你他妈的嘴
Who hired you?
谁雇的你？
I don't know his fucking name!
我不知道他妈的名字！
-Who hired you? -No, no, no.
-谁雇的你？  -不，不，不
I swear. I swear it's the truth.
我发誓 我发誓 我说的是真的
It's the truth. I never ask their names.
是真的 我从来不问他们的名字
They never tell.
他们从来不说
Oh, goddamn you, motherfucker!
噢，妈的，混的！
God...! Oh, goddamn!
天呐…！噢！妈的！
Oh, no. Oh, please. Please.
噢，不，求你了
-I know you're gonna tell me something. -I don't know shit.
-我知道你会告诉我一些事情  -我一点都不知道
I swear before God and eight motherfucking white people, all right?
我在上帝和8个白人面前发誓，好吗？
-Look. Look. -No, no, no.
-看着，看着  -不，不不不
No, no, no.
不，不不不
-The tapes. The tapes. -Where?
-录音带，录音带  -哪儿？
Over there in the cabinet. Go, look.
在那边的柜子里 过去看看
First one. Right there. Go look. Right there.
第一个，就是那儿 去看看，就是那儿
Right there, right there.
就是那儿，就是那儿
First cabinet.
第一个橱柜
Second shelf, third tray, first cassette.
第二个架子，第三个托盘，第一盒带子
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That one. That one.
对  对，那个，那个
"Tape one. Doucett."
录音带一，杜塞特
Go ahead, play it. Listen to it.
播放，去听听
I don't know who he is. I never get names.
我不知道他是谁 我从来不知道名字
I swear.
我发誓
Sir, for a very long time,
先生，很长一段时间
we have served a very elite group of clients.
我们只为一小部分精英客户服务
Now, I surmise that you've encountered one such individual.
现在，我觉得你已经是那一小部分的一员
That's the only way you received this number.
这是你能得到这个号码的唯一方式
Correct.
对
Sir, this business existed long before my tenure
先生，这种服务在我来之前就一直有
and will continue long after I'm gone.
也会在我走之后继续有
Never has a released guest made its existence known
外面的世界绝不会有人
to the outside world.
知道从这儿释放的人
-You've convinced me.  -Good.
-你说服了我  -好
How long will we have the pleasure
我们有幸能
of entertaining this Mr. Doucett as a guest?
将这位杜塞特先生作为客人留多久？
Twenty years.
20年
Get your asses up here now.
现在都给我过来
Open the door!
开门！
-See? -Chaney!
-看到了吧？  -钱尼！
I told you.
我告诉过你
Well, do we?
那我们？
-You tell those motherfuckers... -Tell them what?
-你告诉那些混蛋…  -告诉他们什么？
Aah! Get the fuck away from the door!
啊！离门远点！
Move away from the fucking door!
离门远点！
You hear me say get away? Get away from the door.
你听到我说离远点吗？离门远点！
Back the fuck up! Back up!
退后！退后！
All right!
好！
-Easy. Easy now. -Back up!
-放松，放松  -后退！
Easy. Easy.
放松 放松
You're not gonna get away with this, Joe.
你逃不掉的，乔
-Back up. -Easy. Easy. Easy, Joe.
-后退  -放松，放松，乔
-Now! -Get him!
-就是现在！  -抓住他！
-Get his ass! He killed Marco? -Yeah, yeah, they killed Marco.
-抓住他！他杀了马可？  -是，是的，他杀了马可
Son of a bitch.
混蛋
Fuck!
操！
Oh, my God.
噢，我的天呐
You must take care of yourself.
你要照顾好你自己
The fun is only just beginning.
好戏才刚刚开始
Joe.
乔
What the fuck happened?
都他妈发生什么了？
Come on.
来
Come on, Joe.
起来，乔
Hello?
你好？
Marie, he needs to stay down for at least a week.
玛丽，他需要躺至少一星期
Keep movement to a minimum because we don't wanna tear out those sutures.
动作幅度小点，不要把缝合的伤口挣开
He lost a lot of blood, but if he stays down, he should be all right.
他失血很多，但他如果躺着修养，应该会好起来
Half a centimeter difference on some lacerations,
这些割伤偏离半厘米
it could've been a different story.
后果就不一样了
I really appreciate this, Tom.
我很感激，汤姆
You should let me take him to the hospital.
你应该让我把他带到医院
-Why not? -Well, you can't.
-为什么不？  -你就是不能
Somebody tried to kill him. Isn't that something we should call the police over?
有人想要杀他 我们不应该报警吗？
Well, I'm asking you not to.
我让你不要那样做
He isn't a stray dog or a bird with a broken wing, Marie.
他不是一只流浪狗或一只断翅的小鸟，玛丽
I know that you love your lost causes
我知道。你爱你之前失败的努力
but sometimes we meet people who can get us to engage in old thinking.
但是有时我们会碰到一些人 他们会让我们再次用老想法来思考
So, what, you think I'm using again? Is that what you think?
所以，你认为我又在用老想法了？你是这样觉得吗？
Fuck you.
操你妈的
Come in.
进来
Hey. Just wanted to see if you were feeling all right.
嗨 想来看看你是不是好些了
I just wanna take a look at that wound on your back really quickly, if that's okay.
我想看看你背上的伤是不是还好 如果可以的话
Just turn around here.
转过去
Unh. Sorry.
啊 对不起
Okay.
好
Well, it looks like the bleeding has stopped, so that's a good sign.
看起来血已经止住了，这是个好现象
I can't tell you what to do. And I can't tell Marie either.
我不能告诉你要做什么 我也不能告诉玛丽要做什么
But I can tell you this. She's been through a lot.
但是我能告诉你，她经历了很多事
And if there's one thing that she doesn't need any more of from anyone,
如果说有一样东西是她在任何人那里都不再需要的
it's pain.
那就是痛苦
Please don't hurt her.
请不要伤害她
He likes you.
他喜欢你
Do you like him?
你喜欢他吗？
Uh, no. That was a long time ago.
啊，不  那是很久以前了
Well, he still likes you.
他仍然喜欢你
I got your suit cleaned for you.
我把你的西装拿去洗了
They didn't, um... They didn't patch up the hole.
他们没有…没有把破洞缝起来
Can I help you? Here.
我帮你一下？过来
Well, I think you should go.
我觉得你应该走了
Come on, go.
走吧
Come on, get out of here.
走吧，离开这儿
-Go. -Are you serious?
-走  -你是认真的吗？
Don't come back. Go.
别回来了，走吧
Come on, go.
走吧，走
All right, ladies and gentlemen, last call for alcohol.
好了，女士们先生们，这是今天最后一遍酒了
Speak up or forever hold your peace.
大声说话，或者沉默到老
Hello?
你好？
Hello.
你好
Hello. I thought it was time we met.
你好 我觉得我们是时候见见了
Aah! Hey!
啊！嘿！
Hey! What the...?
嗨！发生…？
-Cool. Be cool. -All right, all right.
-冷静点，冷静  -好，好
Kill me now
现在杀了我
and die seconds later never knowing why.
然而几秒之后 你也会原因不明地死去
Stop it!
住手！
I have your daughter. If you'd like to see her alive again,
你女儿在我手上 如果你想再次见到活着的她
I hope we can continue without the violence.
我希望我们可以不用暴力
May I see your list?
我可以看一下你的名单吗？
No.
不
It's of no use to you, trust me.
它对你没用，相信我
I have a proposition for you, Joseph.
我对你有个提议，乔·瑟夫
If you should accept and succeed, you will be greatly rewarded.
如果你接受了并成功了，你会受到很大的奖赏
Firstly, with a video tape recording
首先，一个录影带
of the rape and murder of your wife,
记录你妻子被奸杀的录影带
-Donna Hawthorne. - No! No!
-唐娜·霍桑  -不！不！
Oh, God, no.
哦，天哪，不！
-No. I don't wanna watch it.  -No!
-不，我不想看  -不！
- Please.  -Turn it off.
-求你了  -关掉
Say goodbye. Say goodbye.
说再见，说再见
-Turn it off. -Very well. -Turn it off.
-关掉它  -很好  -关掉它
Secondly, my handwritten confession
第二，我亲笔写的认罪书
to that crime and your kidnapping and imprisonment.
承认对你的绑架和囚禁
Thirdly, and this is my favorite one,
第三，这是我最喜欢的一个
20 million dollars in diamonds.
价值两千万美元的钻石
Lastly, and again, this is only if you should succeed,
最后，当然，再说一遍，只有你成功了之后
I will put a bullet through my brain,
我会把子弹打进我的脑袋里
and you can watch.
而且你能看着
Answer two questions.
回答两个问题
One, who am I?
第一，我是谁？
And two, why did I imprison you for 20 years?
第二，我为什么要囚禁你20年？
If you provide satisfactory answers to both of these questions
如果你能在接下来的46个小时多一点的时间里
in little more than 46 hours from now, you win.
给这两个问题令人满意的答案，你就赢了
Refusal of the challenge brings the same result as failure.
拒绝这项挑战的后果跟你失败了一样
You stay a fugitive from justice,
你将还是一名逃犯
you get no reward, no closure,
没有奖赏，不会结束
and I kill your daughter.
而且我会杀了你的女儿
If you or anyone you know should go to the police
如果你或者其他你认识的人报警
or try to warn Mia, the consequences will be severe.
或是警告米娅，后果会很严重
Especially for her. If you doubt the extent of my will or my reach,
尤其是警告她 如果你怀疑我的意志和能力的范围
I suggest you look in on your friend Marie.
我建议你看一下你的朋友玛丽
That is a live broadcast. My proposition, yes or no?
这是现场直播 我的提议，你接受还是拒绝？
Yes.
接受
It's 629 Cooper Street, and you'd better hurry.
在库珀街629号，你最好快点
Marie.
玛丽
Marie. Marie.
玛丽，玛丽
Hey, Joe.
嗨，乔
I was gonna let Cortez here have some fun with her.
我本想让科特斯跟她玩一玩呢
But now that you're here,
但现在你来了
the bitch can wait.
这个贱人可以等一会儿
-Let's get him up on the table. -Come on.
-把他放在桌子上  -来
Let's go. Let's go.
过来，过来
Pull him up.
把他拉起来
The last person that got the better of me,
上一个占我便宜的人
I tracked her funky ass down
我找到了她
and tortured her for 16 fucking days.
折磨了她16天
Now, compared to what I'm about to do to you,
现在，比起我要对你做的
that was like an ant fucking an elephant.
简直是蚂蚁见大象，不值一提
Yes?
喂？
I'm afraid I can't do that.
我恐怕不能那样做
Reparations must be made.
必须要修理他一下
Indeed it was you who gave me this address
事实上的确是你给我这个地址的
and I appreciate that, but...
我很感激，但是…
No. No, there's nothing you can give me that will stop me...
不，不，没有东西能够阻止我…
"Go to the door."
“去门那里”
-Cortez. -Yo.
-科特斯  -在
Cortez.
科特斯
Move.
闪开
Oh, well, maybe I  can...
哇，好吧，或许我可以…
-I thank you for your generosity, sir. -Damn.
-谢谢你的慷慨，先生  -妈的
And thank you for appreciating my sacrifice.
谢谢你感激我的牺牲
Yes, sir. You have a good evening too.
好的，先生，你也有个愉快的夜晚
You are a lucky motherfucker, you know that?
你是个幸运的混蛋，你知道吗？
Let's go.
我们走
I'm sorry.
对不起
Hey. Hey. Hey.
嗨，嗨，嗨
It's okay. It's okay.
没事了，没事了
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起，对不起，对不起
I have a friend downtown, so I can, um...
我有一个在市区的朋友，所以我可以…
I can stay with her. I don't feel safe here anymore.
我可以跟她住在一块儿 我在这儿感到不安全
Hello?
你好？
Every time he calls, the same music plays.
他每次打电话，都是相同的音乐
Uh, Evergreen Academy.
啊，长青学院
Have you ever heard of that?
你听过它吗？
The prep school I went to.
这是我去的预科学校
This is so weird, I can't find anything.
真奇怪，我找不到任何东西
Here's something.
这里有点信息
Who's Edwina Burke?
谁是埃德温娜·波克？
She was the headmistress. She might know something.
她是校长 她可能会知道些什么
I used to drink a lot.
我过去喝酒，喝很多酒
Yeah, well, I used to drink, and I also did a shitload of other stuff, but...
是的，我过去酗酒，还做一些其他的烂事，但是…
Tonight was actually... It was the first time that I wanted to use again.
今晚实际上是…实际上今晚我第一次想再用一次
I'm glad you're here.
我很高兴你在这儿
Uh, Miss Burke? Edwina Burke from Evergreen Academy?
啊，波克女士？长青学院的埃德温娜·波克？
-Yes. -I was wondering if I could talk to you
-是的  -我想跟你谈一谈
about a former student? Joe Doucett.
你之前的学生乔·杜塞特，可以吗？
-Come in.  -I hope I'm not disturbing you.
-进来吧  -我希望没有打搅你
Not at all. I was just making some tea. Please, sit.
没有 我正在泡茶，请坐
Joseph Doucett.
乔·瑟夫·杜塞特
-Do you remember him? -Of course.
-你记得他吗？  -当然
We had many students gain notoriety, but he was our only murderer.
我们有很多声名狼藉的学生，但他是唯一一个杀人犯
-Thank God. -Well, what if I told you
-感谢上帝  -那么，如果我告诉你
that Joe Doucett is innocent and another man killed his wife?
乔·杜塞特是无辜的，而是另一个人杀了他的妻子？
Someone he knew at Evergreen.
他认识的长青学院的一个人
Why don't you tell me who you are?
不如你告诉我你是谁？
I'm sorry. My name's Marie Sebastian.
我的名字是玛丽·塞巴斯蒂安
Have you heard of the Innocence Project?
你听说过无罪项目吗？
The Innocence Project works with convicted felons.
无罪项目与重罪推定相对应
Joseph disappeared 20 years ago.
乔·瑟夫20年前就失踪了
Excuse me.
不好意思
You really think he didn't do it?
你真的觉得他没犯罪？
We have evidence that suggests he was framed.
我们有证据证明他是被陷害的
That comes as some relief.
这真是让人感到安慰
He was a very handsome boy.
他是个英俊的男孩
Terrible student, but Donna adored him
坏学生，但是唐娜喜欢他
but he never appreciated that or her.
但他从来不感激那份爱，或是她
He was the kind of boy who thought very highly of himself
他是那种非常自负
and no one else.
看不起别人的人
In fact, he could be quite cruel to the others.
实际上，他对其他人可能很残忍
Always with a grin, as if it were a joke.
总是咧嘴笑，像是个笑话
I always felt he was a bit of a lost soul.
我总感觉他有点迷茫
You said you thought it might be another student?
你说你认为可能是另一个学生？
-I'm assuming Joe had enemies? -Many.
-我认为乔应该有敌人？  -很多
But for one to do something so horrible?
但是能做这么可怕事情的人？
That would require a very deep level of hatred.
那得是一种极度的憎恨
Well, was there someone?
那有这样的人吗？
Anyone like that?
能这样做的人？
I honestly don't remember.
我真的不记得了
I drove by the academy this morning.
我今天早上开车经过长青学院
What happened?
发生什么事了？
They took it from him.
他们夺走了它
My father built it brick by brick.
我爸爸一砖一瓦地建造起来它
The board of directors sold it to some faceless corporation
董事会把它卖给了某个不要脸的公司
and the gates have been locked ever since.
大门从那时起就被锁上了
It's all still there.
东西还在那儿
Files, records, the entire history of the school,
文件，记录，整个学校的历史
abandoned.
荒废了
-Bye. -Marie.
-再见  -玛丽
When you first arrived, you said you believe Joe is innocent
你刚到的时候，你说你相信乔“是”无辜的
not was.
不是“曾经是”
I assumed he was dead.
我以为他死了
Thank you.
谢谢
God, you went to school here?
天呐，你在这儿上的学？
A long time ago.
很久以前了
-Let's come back tonight. -Okay.
-我们晚上再来吧  -好
-Hello? -I didn't know him back then.
-你好？  -我当时不认识他
I don't even recognize the name.
我甚至记不得他的名字
Your friends? Maybe they know him.
你的朋友们？或许他们认识他
I haven't seen those assholes in years. I doubt they'd talk to me.
我好几年没见那些混蛋了 我怀疑他们还会不会跟我说话
I hated everything about that fucking place, except you.
我讨厌那个鬼地方的所有东西，除了你
- I'm sorry, Joe.  -No, there's nothing to be sorry about.
-抱歉，乔  -没事，别担心
Let me see what I can find out. Okay?
让我看看我能找到什么，好吗？
All right.
好
We should change your bandage.
我们该换你的绷带了
-Need help? -Yeah, please.
-要帮忙？  -是的，拜托
Sister?
姐姐？
The party you have called is not available. Leave a message.
你所呼叫的号码不能接听 请留言
Joe, it's Chucky. Call me as soon as you get this.
乔，我是查基 你听到留言后尽快回我
It's not about him, it's about her. The whore, remember?
这不是关于男他，是女她 那个妓女，记得吗？
Jesus, Joe, call me.
天啊，乔，给我电话
Chucky?
查基？
You called her a whore.
你叫她妓女
You called her a whore!
你叫她妓女！
Whore! Whore! Whore!
妓女！妓女！妓女！
Adrian Pryce. Adrian Pryce.
艾德里安·普莱斯 艾德里安·普莱斯
I got it.
找到了
"As we begin our preparation for the new year, I'd like to call attention
当我们开始准备新年的时候，我想要你们关注
to the arrival of a new legacy student from the Pryce family, Amanda Pryce."
来自普莱斯家族的新学生，阿曼达·普莱斯
Will you check for Amanda?
你能去找找阿曼达吗？
Nineteen eighty-six.
一九八六年
I got it.
找到了
Amanda Pryce. "It has come to my attention
阿曼达·普莱斯  我注意到
that the Pryce family is relocating to Luxembourg."
普莱斯家族移民到了卢森堡
Do you remember her?
你记得她吗？
Now, hold on.
等一下
Freshwomen should be in their rooms. This is a serious infraction.
大一新女生应该待在她们自己的房间
-Give it back to me. -Hey, Joe, leave her alone.
-还给我  -嗨，乔，别骚扰她
-If she wants to go, let her go. -Donna, shut up.
-如果她想走，让她走  -唐娜，闭嘴
This is sexy. Very sexy. Huh, Chucky?
这很性感，非常性感 对吧，查基？
-Give it back to me. -Aw. What a fucking freak.
-还给我  -啊，真是怪物啊
-Here, douche bag. -Disgusting.
-给你，讨厌鬼  -恶心
-Hey. -Come on.
-嗨  -算了
Joe, let her through.
乔，让她过去
What dorm number are you in?
你宿舍房间号码是多少？
-Come on, let her go. -Aw...
-算了，放过她吧  -啊…
-Really? -That bitch.
-真的吗？  -那个贱人
Chucky, shut the fuck up.
查基，闭上你他妈的嘴
You gonna let her talk to me like that?
你让她那样跟我说话？
I don't care, I'm drunk.
我不管，我喝醉了
Now, let's get back.
现在我们回去吧
I can't be missed.
我不能不去
Here you go.
你看这儿
There. "Family Tragedy in Luxembourg."
那儿  卢森堡的家庭悲剧
We are in the midst of a most unpleasant mess.
我们正在一个非常悲伤的混乱当中
The crime scene indicates a double murder, suicide,
犯罪现场显示双重谋杀，自杀，
and one seriously injured young man.
还有一个受重伤的年轻男性
The names cannot be released at this time
姓名现在还不能发布
awaiting the family identification.
等待家庭的确认
"Son Tells Tale of Murder."
“儿子讲述谋杀故事”
That's him. The man in the greenhouse that night.
就是他 那天晚上在温室的男人
He was her father.
他是她的父亲
Chucky, where are you? Call me.
查基，你在哪儿？打给我
Shh. Shh, Shh, Shh.
嘘…嘘…嘘…嘘
If he kills you, you're not gonna see your daughter.
如果他杀了你，你就见不到你的女儿了
Okay? And if you kill him,
好吗？如果你杀了他
you're still not going to see your daughter.
你还是见不到你的女儿
Just don't go.
不要去
I don't have a choice.
我没得选择
Please.
求你了
I don't want you to go.
我不想让你去
Listen to me.
听我说
You promise me you'll stay in this room.
你答应我，你会留在这件房间里
Hey.
嗨
Don't call anyone,
不要打电话
don't talk to anyone.
不要跟任何人说话
You stay.
你留下
Will you promise?
你答应我？
Yes.
好
- This is Dr. Tom Melby.  -Listen carefully to what I tell you.
-我是汤姆·梅尔比医生  -仔细听我告诉你的
- Is Marie okay?  -Write this down, you'll need directions.
-玛丽还好吗？  -记下来，你会需要这些指引的
I'm ready. Tell me where to go.
我准备好了 告诉我去哪儿
Where's Mia?
米娅在哪儿？
There.
那儿
Where? Where is she?
哪儿？她在哪儿？
Here.
这儿
Quite close by, actually.
实际上，很近
But you will not see her,
但是你见不到她
you will not save her until I have your answers.
你救不了她，除非你告诉你的答案
Please put that away. She will suffer great pain if you do not.
把那个收起来如果你不收起来，她会遭受很大的痛苦
Your reward.
你的奖赏
As I said, I'm a man of my word.
就像我说的，我是个遵守诺言的人
So who am I?
我是谁？
Adrian Doyle Pryce.
艾德里安·道尔·普莱斯
Why did I imprison you for 20 years?
我为什么囚禁你20年？
-You blame me for what happened. -Elaborate.
-你因为你家人的事怪我  -详细点
I saw your sister with a man, down at the greenhouse.
我看见你姐姐和一个男人，在温室
"They were fucking. They were fucking."
他们在性交，他们在性交
-Isn't that what you told everyone? -Yes.
-这不是你告诉所有人的吗？  -是
I told Donna.
我告诉了唐娜
I told Chucky, I told half of Evergreen.
我告诉了查基 我告诉了大半个长青学院的人
Gossip spreads like the plague.
流言像瘟疫一样传播
-Amanda's a whore! Whore! Whore! -Stop it!
-阿曼达是个妓女！妓女！妓女！  -不要说了！
-Whore! Whore! Whore! -Leave me alone!
-妓女！妓女！妓女！  -离我远点！
-Chucky! Stop it now! -Whore! Whore! Whore!
-查基！不要说了！  -妓女！妓女！妓女！
-Chucky! Stop it now! -I didn't do anything!
-查基！不要说了！  -我什么都没做！
You have no idea how difficult it was for Amanda then.
你不知道当时对阿曼达来说有多难
The torture that she endured, all because of you.
她所经受的折磨，都是因为你
Continue.
继续
I didn't know it was your father until today.
我知道今天才知道那是你父亲
The school must have found out what was going on,
学校一定发现了究竟是怎么回事
and he got your family out of the States as fast as possible.
你父亲带你家人尽快离开了美国
I'm only guessing, but running didn't help.
我仅仅是猜测，但是逃离并没有起作用
He must've been afraid of what was coming.
他一定是害怕将要发生的事情
You know nothing of my father.
你一点儿都不了解我的父亲
He knew no fear, only love.
他不知道恐惧，只知道爱
Arthur Pryce was a great man.
亚瑟，普莱斯是个伟大的人
He will always be a great man.
他永远都是伟大的人
What we had together...
我们一起经历的…
was beautiful and special and pure.
是非常美妙、特殊而纯洁的
My father did what he did to honor and preserve that.
我的父亲那样做是为了纪念和保留那份爱
Father.
父亲
Daddy.
爸爸
My father loved my mother.
我父亲爱我的母亲
Daddy.
爸爸
He loved my sister.
他爱我的姐姐
And he loved me.
他爱我
You see, Joseph, my sister Amanda and I thought
你知道了，乔·瑟夫，我姐姐阿曼达和我以为
that what we had with my father would last forever.
我们跟我父亲的关系会持续到永远
That nobody could take it from us.
没有人能从我们身边带走它
And yet, you did.
但是，你夺走了它
And, yes,
是的
that is why I imprisoned you for 20 years.
那就是我囚禁你20年的原因
It seems you've won, Mr. Doucett.
看起来你赢了，杜塞特先生
Take me to Mia.
带我去见米娅
Yes, of course.
好的，当然
Do you know what I find fascinating, Joseph?
你知道我发现一点很有趣，乔·瑟夫？
All this time, you never stopped to ask
一直以来，你从来没有问
the most fundamental question of all.
最基本的问题
Why did I let you go?
我为什么放了你？
Mind your head.
小心你的头
Introducing one of the longest-running shows on television
介绍给你运作时间最长的电视节目
but it had only a single viewer.
但它只有一个观众
You.
你
We adopted Mia shortly after the tragedy.
我们在悲剧之后不久就领养了米娅
Neither her mother or this Doucett murderer
她的母亲和这个杜塞特凶手
had any living relatives.
都没有在世的亲戚
- So we were lucky enough to... -Blessed.
-所以我们很幸运能…  -幸福
Yes, we were blessed.
是，我们很幸福
Isn't it amazing?
这不是很神奇吗？
People just believe whatever they see on television.
人们只相信他们在电视上看到的
Thank you, Ashley. You can go.
谢谢你，阿什利你可以走了
What...?
什么…？
-Joseph. Ha-ha-ha. -No. No. Mia.
-乔·瑟夫  哈哈哈  -不，不，米娅
Mia!
米娅！
Oh, Joseph.
哦，乔·瑟夫
Joseph, that is not your daughter.
乔·瑟夫，那不是你的女儿
Ashley is a musician and very well paid actress
阿什利是一个音乐家和一个薪酬很高的演员
that I've had in my employ since she was 10 years old. Ha-ha-ha.
我从她10岁起就开始雇佣她 哈哈哈
Oh, goodness.
噢，天呐
Enough with the games.
游戏玩够了！
You tell me where she is. You tell me.
你告诉我她在哪儿 你告诉我
Answer the question you never asked.
回答你从来没有问过的问题
Why did I let you go?
我为什么放你走？
You tell me. You tell me.
你告诉我  你告诉我
You know the answer, Joseph.
你知道答案，乔·瑟夫
In your heart of hearts, you know
在你内心深处，你知道
the plain and simple truth.
简单朴素的真相
-Mia. Mia.  -It took a while...
-米娅，米娅  -要花费很长时间…
- Mia. Where are you going?  -To change her name...
-米娅，你去哪儿？  -去改变她的名字…
her records...
她的记录…
to find the right parents.
找到正确的父母
An insensitive mother,
一个感觉迟钝的母亲
a loving father taken from her too soon.
一个过早从她身边被夺走的父亲
It took 20 years to create her.
花了20年来塑造她
A sensitive, caring woman,
一个敏感善解人意的女人
eager to help those in need
渴望去帮助那些需要帮助的人
because she herself had overcome
因为她自己经历了
such a troubled past.
悲惨的过去
The kind of woman who couldn't help
这种控制不住
but fall in love with a man like you...
爱上你这种男人的女人…
Joseph Doucett.
乔·瑟夫·杜塞特
No!
不！
No, no, no! God!
不，不，不！天呐！
No, God, no, please, no!
不，天呐，不，求你了，不！
Please, God, no!
求你了，天呐，不！
-Joe? Joe? -No way, no way, no!
-乔？乔？  -不，不，不！
Aah. No.
啊，不
No, no, no.
不，不，不
No, no, no. You can't hurt her.
不，不，不 你不要伤害她
Who is this?
你是谁？
Leave her out of it, please. Please.
不要把她牵扯进来，求你了，求你了
-Who is this? -Please, please, please.
-你是谁？  -求你了，求你了，求你了
No, don't hurt her.
不，不要伤害她
Hurt me. Hurt me.
伤害我 伤害我
Kill me. Yes, yes, yes.
杀了我 对，对，对
-Shh. -Yes. Kill me. Please.
-嘘  -对，杀了我，求你了
-Please kill me. -Shh. I don't want to kill you, Joseph.
-求你了杀了我  -嘘，我不想杀你，乔·瑟夫
This is why I let you go.
这就是我放你走的原因
Shh.
嘘
So that I could experience this moment with you.
所以我能跟你一起感受这个时刻
So that you could truly understand what I had,
所以你能真实地感受到我经历的
and what you took from me.
和你从我身边夺走的
Heaven make me free of it.
天堂会让我自由的
The rest is silence.
其他都是沉默
"Dear Marie, you will never see me again.
“亲爱的玛丽，你永远不会见到我了
I'm gone from your life forever.
我会永远从你生活中消失
I have done something terrible.
我做了非常可怕的事情
Something unforgivable.
无法原谅的事情
And for it, I must be punished.
为此，我必须接受惩罚
For a short while, I was happy...
这很短的一段时间，我很快乐…
because of you.
因为你
And I will cherish that happiness forever.
我会永远珍藏那份幸福
Marie, I will love you, always.
玛丽，我爱你，永远
But you must forget me.
但是你必须忘记我
Do not waste one more moment of your life thinking about me.
不要浪费你人生的一点一滴来想我
I want you to be with someone who will care for you,
我想要你跟一个关心你的人在一起
watch over you, bring you joy,
照顾你，带给你快乐
not pain.
而不是痛苦
I want you to find happiness with a good man
我想要你跟一个好人幸福生活
who has a good heart.
一个善良的好人
A man unlike me.
一个不会像我这样的人
Goodbye.
再见
Joe."
乔”